## **Barskov Nikita**

Current position

Software Developer at Rystad Energy

Place of birth

Samara, Russia

◆ Place of residence

Oslo, Norway

(1-year residence permit for skilled workers)

**J** +47 902 64 423

**J** +7 927 657 16 10

github.com/nikitabarskov

in linkedin.com/in/nikitabarskov

◀ t.me/nikitabarskov

# **Professional Summary**

I'm a software developer with 3+ years of experience. I focus on solving urgent problems and tasks, the solution of which brings a significant contribution to the development of the product. I try to create a sensible value reliably.

I am not afraid to learn new technologies and methodologies relevant to solving the current problem.

# **Experience**

### Maxifier, Samara, Russia

Intern April 2017 – June 2017

Working on batch processing project in Maxifier as Intern.

Stack: Java, Guice, PostgreSQL, Spark, Hadoop, Aurora, Bazel, GitLab Cl.

**Data Engineer** June 2017 – August 2019

Developing the application for forecasting users interactions with advertising content and its evaluation. Stack: Python/Scala, Spark, Hadoop, Mesos, Docker, MySQL, Akka, Slick, SciPy, Maven, GitHub.

## Rystad Energy, Oslo, Norway

#### **Software Developer**

September 2019 – present

Working on satellite imagery processing application (spatial data processing, object detection, time series analysis). Support legacy forecast and analytics applications.

Stack: Python, PyTorch/FastAl, Pandas, Jupyter, Colab, .Net Framework, C#.

# **Education**

#### Samara University, Samara Russia

#### **Master Degree Student**

September 2017 - June 2019

Data Analysis and Quality Assurance, Average Point 5.0

**Bachelor of Science** 

Sep 2013 – June 2017

Applied Mathematics and Physics, Average Point 4.65

#### **Skills**

**Soft:** focus on rational problem solving, flexible and responsible in communication, understand the importance of team working, and analysis of feedback

Base Skills: mathematics, physics, computer science

**Natural Languages:** Russian (motherlounge), English (intermediate), German (beginner), Norwegian (beginner)

Programming Languages: Python 3, Scala, Java

**Frameworks and libraries:** Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos, Akka, Slick, Docker, Scipy (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib), Scikit-learn, PyTorch, FastAI, Shapely, GeoPandas, Rasterio, Solaris

Build Tools and VCS: Maven, Bazel, Git, Gitlab CI, GitHub

**Others:** knowledge in process cycle of Software Application Development, methodologies, QA, Bussiness and System Analytics